SIMON WONG

Software Engineer & IT Professional

WORK EXPERIENCE

LLUNA - Remote (Feb 2023 - Present)

Lead Software Engineer

Full-stack engineer leading the buildout and modernization of LLUNA's core technology products: the Personal Operating Profile (POP) and TeamOS. Building software that connects people and teams using React, NextJS + Vercel, and Apollo.

IKEA US DIGITAL HUB - Conshohocken, PA (Apr 2021 - Feb 2023)

Senior Software Engineer

Digital Shopping Experience, Conversion

Full-stack engineer supporting IKEA's global e-commerce products. Drove international customer conversion through innovative technical solutions and data-driven experimentation. Building, deploying, and scaling cloud-based micro-applications using React, Node.js, and Google Cloud Platform.

THE VANGUARD GROUP, INC - Malvern, PA (Jul 2015 - Apr 2021)

Software Engineering Chapter Lead

Retail Systems - Client Experience & Digital (Apr 2020 - Apr 2021)

Hybrid player-coach contributing as senior software engineer for Vanguard's Client Experience lab. Re-envisioning the investor's digital experience using modern web technologies including Angular, GraphQL, Node.js, and AWS ECS.

Technical Project Manager

Chief Technology Office - Runtime, Resiliency, & Cloud (Sep 2018 - Apr 2020)

Led DevOps platform engineering team in buildout of Pivotal Cloud Foundry runtime environment in AWS. Promoted Site Reliability Engineering practices through improved availability, observability, and learnings from failure.

EXTRACURRICULAR

THE VANGUARD GROUP, INC

Developer Experience Champion | Jan 2020 - Apr 2021 **TechTalks Conference Lead** | May 2016 - Mar 2020 **Technology Leadership Program** | Jul 2015 - Jul 2017

CHARLIE'S CRUSADERS PET RESCUE

Website Administrator | May 2018 - Present

PENN STATE IFC/PANHELLENIC DANCE MARATHON **Technology Committee Captain** | Apr 2014 - Mar 2015



ABOUT ME

I am a professional software engineer based out of the greater Philadelphia area with experience in technical leadership, web, and mobile development.

My passions include building beautiful software products with a client-centric lens, embracing the DevOps mindset, and crafting an engineering culture that celebrates inclusion and innovation.

EDUCATION

M.S.E. Software Engineering Penn State University '19

B.S. Information Sciences & Technology

Penn State University '15

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- > JavaScript, TypeScript
- > React, Angular, Sass
- > Node.js, Express.js
- > GraphOL, Apollo, urgl
- > Prisma, PostgreSQL
- > Jest, Testing Library, Cypress
- > Optimizely Web & Full-Stack
- > AWS, GCP, Vercel
- > Splunk, Sentry, Datadog
- > CI/CD Pipelines

GET IN TOUCH

www.simonwong.dev

n simonzwong



hello@simonwong.dev